STEPHANIE MATHIS

Atlanta, GA, USA

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sdm1984
Portfolio: https://sdm1984.github.io/Portfolio/GitHub: https://github.com/Sdm1984

PROFILE

Early career technology professional leveraging over 15 years of experience in higher education and media to bring a fresh perspective on how users interact with software platforms. Earned Full-Stack Web Development Certificate from Georgia Institute of Technology and **learned 26 new technologies in 24 weeks**. Demonstrated ability in planning and executing engaging events and programs designed to advise and educate a wide range of audiences. **Combining 5-year media experience**, **delivered**, **and produced creative communications for different channels such as newsletters**, **videos**, **brochures**, **website**, **social media to inform**, **advise**, **and educate clients**. Possesses strong communication and stakeholder management skills while taking a creative approach to problem-solving.

CONTACT

Email: stephaniedmathis@gmail.com

Phone: 803.983.3663

SKILLS

- HTML5
- VSCode
- Slack
- CSS3
- JavaScript ES6+
- APIs
- Node.is
- Bootstrap
- Command Line/Git
- jQuery
- Canva
- Project Management
- Microsoft Office

EDUCATION

Certificate Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp,

Georgia Institute of Technology June 2022

Certificate IDI Qualified Administrator, IDI, LLC Iune 2021

Master of Science International Affairs, Graduated with Distinction

Florida State University Dec 2007

Bachelor of Arts Political Science, African Studies Minor College of Charleston May 2006

WORK EXPERIENCE

International Student & Scholar Advisor (DSO & ARO)

Emory University, Atlanta, GA, May 2019 - Present

- Guided about 4,000 international students and scholars regarding federal immigration and employment regulations.
- Troubleshoot client problems with ISSS Link (Sunapsis) Software.
- Plan and execute all pre-arrival and orientation programs and events.
- Develop and update communications across e-forms, templates, newsletters, and the ISSS website.
- Wrote the content and voiced over OPT and H-1B explainer videos.
- Advise other departments on recruiting, hosting/hiring, and maintaining the status of foreign nationals in F-1, J-1, H-1B, E-3, O-1, and TN immigration status and for permanent residence.

International Student & Scholar Advisor (DSO & ARO)

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, Nov 2017 - May 2019

- Advised approximately 5,000 F-1 & 1,000 J-1 students, scholars, and dependents.
- Led the planning and execution of new student & scholar orientation and delivered presentations each term.
- Prepared internal and external reports related to the international student population.
- Advocated for the GT global community and supported engagement activities & served as the advisor for the GT International Ambassadors.

International Student Services Coordinator (DSO)

Christian Brothers University, Memphis, TN, Nov 2016 - Nov 2017

- Assembled career development programs with the Department of Career Services such as résumé writing workshops & interview tips.
- Worked closely with the cross-functional teams including office staff, directors, academic program officials, and Dean of Students to manage matriculation of admitted international students.
- Provided support to Admissions Office staff members, faculty, and other support units to discuss retention strategies, goals, and supervised student workers.

International Services Coordinator

The National Society of Black Engineers, Alexandria, VA, Dec 2008 - July 2009

- Supported event organization from planning to execution of on- and offcampus programs and events including international workshops, conferences, orientations, leadership summits.
- Organized International Education Week and recruited 300+ new members in Trinidad & Jamaica. Collaborated with the corporate relations team in securing \$50,000 international scholarships and inkind donations from Microsoft for K-12 chapters.
- Developed and wrote content such as articles and case studies for NSBE Publications.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

WellCome | Project Link Collaborator

- Delivered elevator pitch and received praise for designing a visually appealing deck which went beyond the outline by emphasizing the goal of the app contextually.
- Back-end team member and organized the Kanban board.

Password Generator | Project Link Creator

- Modified starter code to create an application that enables users to generate random passwords based on criteria they've selected.
- This app will feature dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by JavaScript code.

Work Day Scheduler | Project Link, Creator

- Developed front-end with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Vanilla JS.
- Created a simple calendar application that allows a user to save events for each hour of the day.
- The Moment.js (https://momentjs.com/) library was used to include the date and time.

PRESENTATIONS

"Bringing the World to Emory" - **Ongoing**

Immigration/Employment Workshops -Ongoing

"Intercultural Communication Training for Emory University's Academic Fellows" 2019-2020

"It's a Different World: Understanding the Benefits of Cultural Diversity and Cross- Cultural Communication in Our Ever-Changing Global Society" Spring 2017

MEDIA EXPERIENCE

Research Planner (FSU Study Abroad Program)

The National Assn. for the Conservation of Nature, Panama, May 2007 - Aug 2007

- Identified inaccessible locations on-site and proposed recommendations to the client on improving trail conditions for people with disabilities.
- Delivered proposals defining steps needed to systematically build an accessible trail.

Iournalist

Freelance, Pinewood, SC, Sep 2015 - Nov 2016

- Planned editorial and marketing content for bloggers and global media clients.
- Adhered to preferred editorial style and format standards and wrote stories accordingly.
- Collected and verified newsworthy information to develop story ideas.
- Received assignments and followed news leads/tips.

Associate News Producer/Writer

CBS Corporation (CBS News 11), Fort Worth, TX, Oct 2014 - Sep 2015

- Managed news broadcasts and oversaw the development of news stories to create a cohesive show.
- Wrote clear and concise content for on-air talent.
- Collaborated with marketing department in developing high-impact, high-reach marketing collateral on a variety of media and organized web content.

News Producer/Reporter

Media General (CBS News 13), Myrtle Beach, SC, Feb 2012 - Sep 2014

- Fostered all aspects of morning show production and supervised a team of 5 members.
- Collaborated with news directors, reporters and anchors and supervised the overall content, flow of news distribution, and executed breaking news stories.
- Worked with Senior Producers to plan the South Carolina 7th Congressional District Debate and filled-in for evening shows.

Associate Producer/Video Editor

South Carolina ETV (PBS Affiliate), Sumter, SC, Feb 2011 - Feb 2012

- Supported all video production phases from pre- to post-production to delivery.
- Aid producers in research and development of show topics.
- Generated and pitched content/news ideas to production team.